hey guys this looks like a fun one it's
made up of four squares and it wants to
know what's this shaded area if you want
to try it on your own pause it right now
cuz I'm going to solve it in 3 2 1 first
step I want to focus on this triangle
right here so let's make it blue and
then I want to zoom in on this region
right here looking at this blue triangle
this angle is a right angle and that's
because we know all of these are squares
and then this angle right here is also a
right angle and that's because it's one
of the angles of this larger Square next
if you ever have two parallel lines and
a line cutting through them it will
always be true that these two angles are
equal to each other these are called
alternate interior angles and this is
the alternate interior angle theorem we
have this exact situation going on here
these two lines are parallel and this
line is cutting through them that means
these two angles are equal to each other
if we look at this pink triangle and
this blue triangle these have two pairs
of corresponding congruent angles that
means the third angles must also be
congruent and now let's pull out these
two triangles and we'll look at those
later next I want to focus on this
square with an area of five that means
that the side lengths are each going to
be square OT of five and if we look at
this square with an area of 20 the side
lengths are each going to be square < TK
of 20 next I want to look at this square
right here the base of the square is <
tk2 +un 5 that means that the side is
also going to beunk 20 +un 5 and let's
move this < tk2 label from the bottom to
the top of this square and now we're
ready to mess around with this blue
right triangle if we label the
hypotenuse C we can do the Pythagorean
theorem we can do < TK 20 2 +un 5^2 is
equal to c^2 and for this first term the
square root and the square will cancel
each other out to give us 20 and same
thing here otk 5^ 2 is going to be 5 20
+ 5 is equal to 25 and we can take the
square root of both sides and we end up
with 5 is equal to C so let's update
this C up here to be five and now that
we have the measurements of the blue
triangle let's update it down here next
I want to focus on the top of this
Square it's going to be equal to < TK 5
+un 20 this is the exact same thing as
the hypotenuse of this pink triangle it
will also beunk 5 + < tk2 and < tk2 can
be split up as < TK 4 * 5 and then this
can be split up into < TK 4 * < TK 5 and
< TK 4 is equal to 2 so it ends up being
2un 5 so now we can simplify this side
length if we add up < TK 5 + 2un 5 it
ends up being 3un 5 and now we're almost
done they want to know what's the Shaded
area we called this length down here s
that is the same as the base of our pink
Square so once we know s we know the
answer to our question the area of this
pink square is going to be s s so let's
solve for S I want to give this pink
triangle the same orientation as the
blue triangle all three of these
corresponding pairs of angles are
congruent which means these two
triangles are similar that means we can
set up a proportion for their
corresponding sides we have 3un 5 over 5
is going to be equal to S over < tk2 and
then we can cross multiply which gives
us 5S is = to 3un 5 * < tk2 and then
this < TK 5 < tk2 can be combined into <
TK 5 * 20 that's going to be < TK of 100
which is equal to 10 and 3 * 10 is equal
to 30 and after we divide both sides by
5 we get S is equal to 6 now we're ready
to plug this in we can plug in 6 for
this s and 6 s is equal to 36 and let's
give it a label of unit squared and that
is the answer to our question the area
of this shaded region is 36 units
squared let's put a box around it how
exciting